<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Miker]]></title>
  <link href="http://rowehl.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rowehl.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-25T01:15:11-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://rowehl.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mike Rowehl]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rebooting an Engineering Organization]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2013/05/25/rebooting-an-engineering-organization/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-25T00:06:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2013/05/25/rebooting-an-engineering-organization</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When Metaresolver got purchased by Millennial Media I figured I would have
some bits of strategic input around how to approach the evolving mobile media
models, and then I would help hack through some of the prototypes and early
systems in those new lines of business. That version was interesting cause of
the market position that Millennial has, and because it&#8217;s been a really long
time since I&#8217;ve worked with a group larger than 10 people. But I had assumed
that the challenging part was going to be keeping myself from getting
overly bored by the rate of progress so I could hang out long enough to
make a difference.</p>

<p>And then when our deal actually formally closed the founding CTO from
Millennial left at the same time. In the wake of
that the decision was made: it was time for a major restructuring on the
technology side of Millennial. The company has a tremendous market position,
but we&#8217;ve been having trouble capitalizing on it. We needed to start
updating the way Millennial practices engineering so that it could keep at
the front of a rapidly evolving market. Suddenly being bored wasn&#8217;t on my
list of concerns any more.</p>

<p>The part of the reboot that I&#8217;ve been most actively involved in is down in the
technical details of revamping how engineers get their daily work done. There
are some really simple parts that everyone has already been talking about
forever, and just needed some focused attention. Not everything is running
through a continuous integration process, and lots of it doesn&#8217;t have
automated testing it can be run through. The organization as a whole has
fallen so far into the antipatterns of manual QA and the
<a href="http://www.rendell.org/pebble/software/2010/02/09/1265756844985.html">high ceremony release vehicle</a>
that there&#8217;s a ton of resistance around fixing the deployment process. But
fortunately it&#8217;s 2013 now, even in Baltimore. So hopefully it&#8217;s just a matter
of time before everyone understands the value of getting working code up into
production quickly, and that there are better ways to make sure we enforce the
&#8220;working code&#8221; bit than throwing bodies and forms at the issue.</p>

<p>The overall goal is to get us to something that looks much more like a
continuous delivery process. There are some patterns that are just so second
nature to me and everyone I&#8217;ve worked with over the last few years that I
frequently forget they&#8217;re not universal yet. Everything I&#8217;ve worked on over
the last few years has evolved in relatively the same direction: deployments
are single script (or single git push) affairs, the scripts write some
info into a shared channel so that people know what went out, the operational
monitors are visible to everyone and well defined, and rolling back if those
monitors go sideways is always part of the plan. It&#8217;s awesome.</p>

<p>So when I ask someone about deployment tools and they start to describe
something that has a cabal of approvers meeting to bless things and change
notification forms I can only stand there stunned. Well, first I throw up in
my mouth a little bit, and then I stand there stunned.</p>

<p>Guess this is what I get for leaving Silicon Valley without proper backup.
It&#8217;s a backwards and fucked up place out here my friends, and I can&#8217;t
say I recommend it at all. But I&#8217;ve started to pull together the
necessary backup and my plan is to fix at least a small part of it before
my next startup. You&#8217;re welcome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I Suck at Angel Investing, and My Plan]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2013/03/09/why-i-suck-at-angel-investing/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-09T21:23:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2013/03/09/why-i-suck-at-angel-investing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve done a bunch of angel investing over the last few years. And I&#8217;ve decided
I&#8217;m no good at it. The market, so far, seems to agree with me. Most of the
investments I&#8217;ve done are nowhere, frequently not even making it to launch.
That&#8217;s okay actually, not a big deal.</p>

<p>What the realization has forced me to do is cycle back on why I was angel
investing in the first place. I really wanted to do it so that I could help
friends realize their dreams. There are tons of people I&#8217;ve worked with over
the years who have fantastic skills and often correspondingly focused vision.
That sounded like a great investment thesis to me, folks who I&#8217;ve worked with
directly.
And I figured that giving them
some money to help out when they were starting on a new effort would be a great
way to share in the adventure.</p>

<p>However, there&#8217;s a bunch of stuff I missed the first time around:</p>

<ul>
<li>I&#8217;m bad at filtering ideas. I think everything is a good idea. That seems to
just be a bias of exuberance and having been an operator myself for the last
20 years. I project how I would attack the problems, and assume if it&#8217;s
something I can execute on certainly other people can. In retrospect that was
dumb, and I should have realized this one in advance.</li>
<li>I thought I would be able to directly help out. I&#8217;ve been building businesses
and technology for 20 years, I normally have a lot to contribute. However,
once I&#8217;m an investor teams tend not to come back to me for help.
I think cause most of them only want to come back with good news, they&#8217;re
kinda embarrassed to come back to an investor for help. That&#8217;s just dumb on
their part. I use my investors for help all the time, and they&#8217;re always
supportive, encouraging, and effective. Trying to run success theatre is dumb.</li>
<li>Venture funded businesses, and the current crop of startups in particular,
are really focused on short term financial gain. There&#8217;s not really much
&#8220;realizing dreams&#8221;. Unless your dream is to flip a company to Google. So it&#8217;s
ended up being kinda boring. If it was even in there to begin with, vision
frequently takes a back seat. And the companies just randomly pivot over and
over, flailing around trying to find instant product market fit and 10x
compounding daily growth cause they think it&#8217;s rational to expect that. Of
course they never do.</li>
<li>At the levels I&#8217;ve been investing (normally very small stuff like $10k to
$25k, the occasional $50k) it just doesn&#8217;t shift the needle. Coupled with
folks not coming back for help: I&#8217;m not getting any leverage out of the
investment and the teams aren&#8217;t getting any leverage out of the money.</li>
</ul>


<p>So, of course, the real next question should be how do I fix it? I could just
give up on trying to make awesome things happen. But that&#8217;s not really my style.
I&#8217;ve also been tempted to dust off lots of stuff I learned from Churn Labs and
try to run a similar effort, with significant tweaks this time around. That
whole line of thinking is worth a post of its own actually.</p>

<p>Recently I had to do some legal work that required me to actually go through
and enumerate all my assets in one place. So the shares I have in companies
that I&#8217;ve invested in ended up side by side with the list of companies I have
shares from cause I&#8217;m advising them. And the difference was shocking. The folks
I spend a bit of time with every month, they&#8217;re rocking it. That says to me
there might be something to me being able to directly help out. Now correlation
is not causation, I&#8217;m fully aware. So it might just be that the folks who
aren&#8217;t asking me for money are predisposed to a working style that increases the
chance of success, and it really doesn&#8217;t have anything to do with me at all. But
right now it&#8217;s a working hypothesis at least, and I&#8217;m willing to test it.</p>

<p>There are actually a bunch of different methodologies I&#8217;ve been thinking about
to put that test into play. But then my current company got bought (which, by
the way, I&#8217;m using as an additional point in support of my hypothesis :-P), and
for once I&#8217;m finally enthusiastic about working with the new team for a good
chunk of time. So that severely cuts down on the plans I can realistically put
into action over the next few years.</p>

<p>That means if I want to keep involved it really needs to be as investor, but I
needed to figure out how to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Work on things that are going to change the world in a positive way, and that
me and the team will be proud of.</li>
<li>Make sure there&#8217;s a way to keep myself directly involved, so I can figure out
if I actually make a difference at all. I need to figure out a nice
scientific approach to determine this still.</li>
<li>Provide real leverage to the teams.</li>
</ul>


<p>There are tons of incubators and accelerators out there now, and I didn&#8217;t want
to be just another &#8220;me too&#8221; in a sea of mediocrity. Fortunately they tend to
really focus on different businesses than I would like to go after, so I&#8217;m
thinking I can do something that isn&#8217;t duplicative. There are tons and tons of
little companies spun up to try to exploit tiny gaps in existing markets, and
relatively few looking to open up new areas. In other words there aren&#8217;t too
many <a href="http://www.spacex.com/">SpaceX</a> style projects out there. And I would
like there to be.</p>

<p>My plan is to start filtering the projects I work
with using a completely different set of criteria going forward, to take a much
more active and direct role in the projects, and to start investing in the
$250k to $500k range instead. I&#8217;ve got one of these starting to come together
now, and a few other discussions with folks about the overall model. I think
the right model for myself is actually to keep this to one project at a time,
just to keep myself and the team focused. So I&#8217;m probably going to also start
being a lot more low volume than I have been in the past.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use of Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2013/02/06/use-of-time/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-06T12:48:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2013/02/06/use-of-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love the idea behind social media services, helping to connect people and
strengthen relationships. However I don&#8217;t think most are actually fulfilling
on that vision. Sure, you can stay connected with friends. But your goals and
the goals of the social service itself frequently aren&#8217;t aligned. The desire
of social media services to drive the metrics they want based on your
connections to friends and family have resulted in systems that
prey on base urges. The result is systems that drive themselves off addiction
loops. In the end they&#8217;re like overeating or
smoking, bad habits. And I assume most people will look to weed out those
behaviors in the interest of their overall health. That&#8217;s my view at least, so
I took the plunge and deleted my Facebook account about a year ago.</p>

<p>At about the same time I decided to crank down a lot of my tech news
consumption, and filter down the folks I follow on Twitter to people who
regularly post things that are uniquely amusing or valuable. I had realized
what I was really trying to do was:</p>

<ul>
<li>make sure I had a good spread of new info coming in to keep generally informed</li>
<li>keep on top of what was going on in my industry</li>
</ul>


<p>So I focused on directly solving those problems instead of having
someone else try to correct for them by proxy. The first part was
kicking back up my long-form reading habit, I started downloading and
consuming lots of Kindle books. When we were working on Churn Labs I wanted to
learn more about places that created long periods with high levels of
innovation. In the info I was finding online I commonly came across the same
examples over and over. Places like Florence during the period of the Medici
family, or Apple, or Corning. But most of those posts online referenced
books for details. In following up the references and just trying to get some
details I picked up a few books and read them through.</p>

<p>At the time it had been a while since I sat down and read a book front to back
that wasn&#8217;t either sci-fi or highly technical. I found that for the purposes
of &#8220;researching&#8221; something, trying to dig into a new topic and understanding
it well enough to be able to make a mental framework and form personal
opinions, I was getting a lot more out of just reading long-form writing.
When it comes to picking up a new subject most online resources don&#8217;t do a
great job.
I think that&#8217;s why there&#8217;s so much attention right now
being thrown into &#8220;online learning.&#8221; The Internet is a fantastic way to
keep up to date with a topic you already understand. But it&#8217;s generally falling
flat when it comes to getting up to speed with something new. Fortunately for
me I pick things up relatively well in written form, and I&#8217;m pretty good at
filling in practical experience on my own. So when I hit something new,
sometimes I&#8217;ll follow up the cursory Wikipedia overview with a book if the
topic seems interesting enough. It can get
to be an expensive habit, but I&#8217;m finding it to be well worth it.
Hopefully soon all these education startups will make free resources I can use
instead, but for now I&#8217;m sticking to the books.</p>

<p>Listening to podcasts has also helped a good deal with getting an overview.
A bunch of the topics I&#8217;m interesting in following at a high level. I don&#8217;t
have the background to follow all the details of new info, but I like to at
least keep informed about major advances in science or engineering. Audio
format delivery seems to be great for that. Lots of the podcasters keep things
high level, I assume cause that&#8217;s best suited to the medium. So
adding just a few shows like the Economist and Science Friday has made me feel
like I&#8217;m pretty well on top of all the stuff I really care about. And I just
use an app (Stitcher on Android for me) so I can listen to the shows while I
walk to/from the train station. Fills up time that wasn&#8217;t really being well
utilized before.</p>

<p>Then I had to figure out how to keep up with the details of the industry
I&#8217;m working in. Or at least I thought I had to. Turns out that the generic
information sources plus directly operating in the industry was already
feeding me more than enough data. I lost a lot of noise by not following the
tech industry coverage. And I figured keeping on top of daily events was
necessary for conversations with other folks in the industry, otherwise you
seem ignorant when someone asks you about a hot topic.
But I found that with the noise gone I had stronger
opinions and better judgment anyway, and the discussions I had were actually
higher quality. Probably cause I had spent more time exploring and
validating my own viewpoint, so I had a lot more to contribute to
conversations.</p>

<p>Every now and again, there&#8217;s something that&#8217;s absolutely essential for me to
catch quickly. What I&#8217;m finding is that normally someone will forward it
to me. Usually to get my opinion on it.
And I find that cause I&#8217;m consuming things outside the channels most
folks pick through, I can serve that same role for others. Really, that&#8217;s my
&#8220;social network&#8221; doing what I originally hoped it would do. Turns out the
social tools were standing in the way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Resurrection]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2013/02/04/resurrection/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-04T23:29:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2013/02/04/resurrection</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This blog has been dormant for a long time, but I&#8217;ve decided to start it back
up. I created the site cause I wanted a Wordpress install
I could test my PalmOS based mobile blogging client against. But once I had
the site
up and running I started tossing all sorts of random stuff in. Everything from
my own thoughts on <a href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/04/02/high-availability-nfs/">scalability</a>
to summaries of events
about <a href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2005/04/15/make-almost-anything/">the FabLab</a>.
However, after a few years of tossing all sorts of random stuff in here I
started to really focus on mobile, so I
created a mobile specific site called
<a href="http://thisismobility.com/blog">This is Mobility</a> so that I wouldn&#8217;t have
everything all jumbled together. Then with
so much interesting stuff happening in mobile this blog eventually fell into
disuse. And it&#8217;s remained unused since 2006.</p>

<p>Recently I&#8217;ve felt getting a little more randomness going again is a good
idea. And I&#8217;m really happy I kept all these blog posts around to read,
so I could get a peek back into my mind 10 years ago and remind myself what it
was like. When I started reading through these posts I figured that&#8217;s all I
would do, read and then put it aside. But I realized how different my
thought process was a few years ago. And not just cause I was young and
naive, but because I was looking at things without the encumbrance of much
bias. &#8221;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shoshin">Beginner&#8217;s mind</a>&#8221; is probably
the best term for it. That beginners mind
decided that Linux and open source were a good bet for building online
services. And that beginners mind decided that homesteading a spot in the
mobile world was a good idea back in 2003. I wouldn&#8217;t pass on getting a bit
more of that beginners mind, and it seemed like writing
here again could help with that process. With the site being 10 years
old, it seemed somehow proper to bring it back.</p>

<p>Of course, some updating needed to be done. While I love Wordpress for
some things, I&#8217;m also getting tired of it getting exploited and abused cause I
pay so little attention to it. It&#8217;s my own fault for not updating it, but I
really like the option of swapping to something I don&#8217;t need to pay attention
to instead of modifying my behavior.  So I swapped over to using
<a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>,
which
uses post files written in markdown to generate the site as a static set of
pages (hat tip to <a href="http://fusion94.org/">Tony</a> for the suggestion).
Thanks to a fantastic set of scripts called
<a href="https://github.com/thomasf/exitwp">exitwp</a> I was able to move
an export of my Wordpress data right into Octopress friendly format.
Yay! That should be the end of Viagra and Levitra ads randomly
appearing at the end of my posts. And as a bonus I can publish the whole thing
through Github Pages, and store the source in Github. Which I was doing with
the rowehl.com site anyway, but had to take special care to backup the
database to keep blog posts safe. Now it&#8217;s all just one repo.
And cause the pages are hosted directly off Github, when I crash
my personal server doing Linux distro hackery I don&#8217;t take down rowehl.com.</p>

<p>Also nice about Octopress - the default profile takes a responsive
approach. So now my personal blog looks better on mobile than my mobile
focused blog. With the way the Octopress templates and plugins are
structured it was pretty easy to make some style changes, swap in some fonts
that make the site look a little less amateur hour. I got rid of commenting
all together and have added some share buttons instead, cause that&#8217;s how the
world works now. Everyone already has their own place to speak, so why put
their thoughts into my database? And again, once less thing for me to worry
about.</p>

<p>In the end, actually not much effort at all. And I&#8217;m really happy with how it
works. Now I have a place to write about all that other
not-specifically-mobile stuff like cool bits of open source, programming,
emerging technologies, and startups. And to remind myself just how far things
have come, I dug up and posted the
<a href="https://github.com/mikerowehl/vagablog">source code</a> to the Treo650 blogging
app that kicked this whole thing off 10 years ago.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu - Sun JDK Graphical Install Only?]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/09/20/ubuntu-sun-jdk-graphical-install-only/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-20T08:01:18-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/09/20/ubuntu-sun-jdk-graphical-install-only</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was just installing the Sun JDK on my workstation at the office, and when I tried the obvious: apt-get install sun-java5-bin got an error message about not being able to find a license. Interesting, thought I, &#8220;there must be a higher level package wrappering this whole thing that deposits a license file somewhere for the apt-get process to pick up&#8221;. A bunch  of searching around in the repository listings turned up no java license related packages.</p>

<p>You find where <a href="http://www.aspma.com/downloads/">download mp3 music</a> on player, You need <a href="http://www.aspma.com/download/">mp3 music download</a> from online mp3 archive</p>

<p>So I did a search and ended up with <a href="https://jdk-distros.dev.java.net/ubuntu.html">this description of installing Java under Ubuntu</a> which says pretty much what I was doing, except using the graphical package manager instead. &#8220;How lame would it be if you needed to install Java using the Synaptic package manager instead of the command line?&#8221; Not lame enough to discourage doing it apparently. If you&#8217;re looking to install Java under Ubuntu you might have to use the package manager instead of apt-get in order to do it. Next time you see Java people throw rotten fruit at them to let them know how you feel about that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Blue Pills with a Whiskey Back Please]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/09/18/two-blue-pills-with-a-whiskey-back-please/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-18T19:21:23-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/09/18/two-blue-pills-with-a-whiskey-back-please</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The surreal thought for today: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laurence_Fishburne">Lawrence Fishburne</a>, Morpheus from The Matrix, was <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cowboy_Curtis">Cowboy Curtis</a> on Pee Wee&#8217;s Playhouse. I was wondering why Pee Wee ended up in the Adult Swim lineup. I get it now. Joke&#8217;s over. You can make it stop.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SpellBound Firefox Plugin, Dev Version]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/09/18/spellbound-firefox-plugin-dev-version/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-18T09:16:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/09/18/spellbound-firefox-plugin-dev-version</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apparently Firefox 2 has inline spellcheck right out of the box.  Werd, I&#8217;m looking forward to it.  However, my Ubuntu systems still have Firefox 1.5.x and I don&#8217;t want to start mucking around now that I&#8217;ve just started accepting I don&#8217;t need to build everything by hand. Start pulling on that thread again and whole thing comes apart!</p>

<p>Normally I use a plugin for spell checking, but it stopped working a few updates ago. Firefox or the extension claims that they are no longer friends. So I was very happy to find the <a href="http://forums.mozillazine.org/viewtopic.php?t=351130">development preview</a> of SpellBound, which not only works with the current Firefox releases under Ubuntu, but does inline spellcheck. Double w00t to that one.  I have it installed at home, as long as it doesn&#8217;t cause any problems I&#8217;ll put it in here at work too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Subversion Book]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/09/15/subversion-book/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-15T05:46:37-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/09/15/subversion-book</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been giving myself a svn refresher so that we can move over to it, and I hit this in the <a href="http://svnbook.red-bean.com/nightly/en/svn.reposadmin.maint.html">maintenance tools documentation page</a> and it made me laugh out loud:</p>

<blockquote><p>This output is human-readable, meaning items like the datestamp are displayed using a textual representation instead of something more obscure (such as the number of nanoseconds since the Tasty Freeze guy drove by).</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You've Stayed Up Too Late When]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/09/10/youve-stayed-up-too-late-when/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-10T00:15:47-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/09/10/youve-stayed-up-too-late-when</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You know you&#8217;ve acidentally let your bedtime slip too close to sunrise when you&#8217;re flipping through the onscreen TV guide and MTV actually lists &#8220;Music Videos&#8221; as currently showing. No need to look at the time, when a thing like that happens you know that either the sun is about to come up or you&#8217;ve somehow ended up in the 80&#8217;s.  Flock of Seagulls anyone?  Don&#8217;t laugh, they&#8217;re <a href="http://www.oz.net/~davester/AFOS/">on tour</a>. On second thought, go ahead and laugh.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hilton Ninja]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/09/06/hilton-ninja/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-06T05:25:19-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/09/06/hilton-ninja</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.ninjastrikeforce.com/?p=100">Paris Hilton has been named an honorary member of the CDC Ninja Strike Force</a>.  A very high honor indeed. No word yet on wether she&#8217;ll also get the ability to blow shit up with heat rays from her eyes, like the other Ninja Strike Force members are able to do. We know she&#8217;s definitely got the backstabbing down pat though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HOPE Six Audio Online]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/08/25/hope-six-audio-online/"/>
    <updated>2006-08-25T05:57:27-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/08/25/hope-six-audio-online</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The full <a href="http://www.hopenumbersix.net/speakers.html">set of audio from the HOPE six conference</a> is online now. The conf happened just before DEFCON and I hear it has some fantastic stuff that didn&#8217;t show up in Vegas. Download and share!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[http_load for Request Replay]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/08/23/http_load-for-request-replay/"/>
    <updated>2006-08-23T19:05:49-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/08/23/http_load-for-request-replay</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://talks.php.net/show/oscon06/0">presentation that Rasmus gave at OSCON</a> this year seems to have kicked some ass. I missed the conf, but got a bunch of interesting info from the slides. In particular I hadn&#8217;t used <a href="http://www.acme.com/software/http_load/">http_load</a> before. Part of what I&#8217;ve been doing at AdMob is taking a look at performance and scaling, so that was a great find. It&#8217;s exactly the set of controls and measurements I normally start out with, and it really does run very efficiently in terms of not loading down the system that http_load is running on.</p>

<p>Just about the only thing that didn&#8217;t work the way I wanted was the random selection from the url list file. I wanted to replay a set of traffic in order, so I <a href="http://www.rowehl.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2006/08/http_load-miker-01patch.txt">hacked up an -orderedurls option</a> to select from the url list sequentially (repeating the list once you get to the end) instead of randomly choosing. Reading the whole file in and parsing it probably isn&#8217;t the way to go for this particular usage, so I&#8217;ll have to clean it up when the traffic segments I&#8217;m playing get into the millions instead of just the tens of thousands. But it works great for now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Lappy]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/08/18/linux-lappy/"/>
    <updated>2006-08-18T02:23:23-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/08/18/linux-lappy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s just about New Laptop Time. Not quite, but almost. Being a Linux only user it&#8217;s always an adventure trying to figure out what hardware to get. Hardware support has definitely gotten better under Linux, but figuring out what actually lives inside the system you&#8217;re thinking about picking up at deep discount from Office Max certainly has not. And I&#8217;m not a dual-booter either. I don&#8217;t have Windows to fall back on should something not work on my laptop. I take a scorched earth approach to Windows on my hardware, and generally wipe and repave the whole thing. Especially if it&#8217;s my personal laptop, which is what I plan for this to be.</p>

<p>Currently I&#8217;m leaning very heavily toward <a href="http://www.thinkwiki.org/wiki/Category:X41_Tablet">the Thinkpad X41 tablet</a>. It looks like there&#8217;s good X support for a bunch of stuff that&#8217;s traditionally a pain in the ass under Linux. Screen rotation seems to be working (without restarting X, thank god), the input driver for the touchscreen, power management (including frequency scaling), and wireless using ipw2200. Anyone out there with an X41 tried Linux and care to toss in some comments before I pick one of the things up? It&#8217;s hard to tell from wiki postings just how painful is it to get the thing actually setup, and there&#8217;s always the chance that the instructions on the wiki are wrong or incomplete.</p>

<p>On a very much related note, anyone know a good shop in the San Francisco Bay Area that could come up with some Pimp My Ride style dashboard mounting and wiring hookups for my car?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ZeroOne San Jose Art Festival]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/08/07/zeroone-san-jose-art-festival/"/>
    <updated>2006-08-07T02:29:07-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/08/07/zeroone-san-jose-art-festival</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week (August 7th to 13th 2006) is the <a href="http://www.01sj.org/">ZeroOne Arts Festival in San Jose</a>. There was a <a href="http://www.futuresalon.org/2005/02/art_on_the_edge.html">great presentation at Future Salon by one of the ZeroOne staff members</a> where he tossed out a dizzying number of art projects that blend in technology in tantalizing ways. And if the interesting art projects weren&#8217;t enough to get you down there on their own, on Friday there&#8217;s a <a href="http://01sj.org/content/view/217/52/">Survival Research Labs</a> exhibition:</p>

<blockquote><p>&#8230;it’s monster machine, meets hovercraft, meets huge sculptural creatures, meets fire.</p></blockquote>

<p>What better way to spend a Friday night? I have just one question.. tickets through Ticketmaster?  Is that part of the tongue in cheek techno-social commentary? That despite the rapid advance of technology in general the only way to throw a huge ticketed real world event is to use Ticketmaster? We&#8217;ll have to work on a project for the next one that fixes that issue.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Diet of Monkey Chow]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/06/06/a-diet-of-monkey-chow/"/>
    <updated>2006-06-06T09:06:28-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/06/06/a-diet-of-monkey-chow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is pure genius! I&#8217;m so disappointed I didn&#8217;t think of it first. A guy trying to <a href="http://www.angryman.ca/monkey.html">live on a diet of pelletized monkey food</a>. FANTASTIC! If it works and he doesn&#8217;t die I&#8217;m definitely doing it. If he does die&#8230; I give myself about a 50-50 chance of still trying it. I should start a run of packaging for the new <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bachelor_Chow#Bachelor_Chow">Futurama style &#8220;Bachelor Chow&#8221;</a> product just in case. I&#8217;ll probably have to wait a while to add flavor however.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Quarter of a Million Spam Messages]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/06/05/a-quarter-of-a-million-spam-messages/"/>
    <updated>2006-06-05T03:00:52-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/06/05/a-quarter-of-a-million-spam-messages</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m at almost a quarter of a million spam messages (249,744 to be precise, by the time I post this it should be more than 250 thousand) caught by <a href="http://akismet.com/">Akismet</a> so far. I <a href="http://www.rowehl.com/blog/?p=605">turned Akismet on in January of this year</a>. That&#8217;s more than 50,000 spam messages a month. According to the Akismet site 92% of the comments it sees are spam.</p>

<p>The problem is very unevenly distributed however. I have a few other blogs out there, and they tend to get more like a few hundred spam messages a month. I just wanted to point that out given the degree of blowup I see when things happen like <a href="http://announcements.engadget.com/2006/05/30/comments-switched-off/">someone has to turn off comments for a while</a>. The spam problem is not uniformly distributed, just because you get a managable ammount of spam comments that doesn&#8217;t mean someone who blogs about just about the same stuff isn&#8217;t getting hundreds of times more.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Web 2.0 Cease and Desist and Self Healing Systems]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/05/25/the-web-20-cease-and-desist-and-self-healing-systems/"/>
    <updated>2006-05-25T11:40:29-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/05/25/the-web-20-cease-and-desist-and-self-healing-systems</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I need to post a <a href="http://www.tomrafteryit.net/oreilly-trademarks-web-20-and-sets-lawyers-on-itcork/">pointer to the story about CMP sending a conference a C&D; letter on behalf of O&#8217;Reilly</a>. I&#8217;m sure Tim has nothing to do with it, and I&#8217;m sure it&#8217;ll go away without much fuss in the end, probably just being throwoff of the corporate machine and the result of the right hand not knowing what the left hand is doing. And of course having lawyers involved, which always screws things up. But it is interesting that something like this would happen in relation to a company that has built its business on being ahead of the knowledge curve, and I would say doing it successfully.</p>

<p>Things like this are bound to happen in any organization/company once the size gets beyond a certain threshold. Perhaps not quite this ridiculous in most cases, but there will be some evidence of lack of syncronization and goal mismatches. In the real world normally this stuff gets cleared up pretty quick. Tim pops up and says &#8220;wow, we didn&#8217;t mean to do that, sorry!&#8221; or someone at CMP chews the lawyers out and releases a statement&#8230; whatever. The point being that inconsistencies and unexpected situations are generally noticed and dealt with. Outside the blogospere at least. Inside the blogosphere they can live on forever, but that&#8217;s really a whole seperate issue.</p>

<p>Odd situations like that tend to cause failures in software though. When something unexpected comes up within a system it&#8217;s generally catastrophic. When something unexpected comes up during an interaction between systems you&#8217;re sometimes lucky just to find out what happened after the fact. I&#8217;ve been thinking about self healing systems recently, although I can&#8217;t remember what might have kicked it off. And after reading this realized that almost all human designed systems are relatively fragile and rigid. Law being one of the obvious areas of intersection between codification and human behavior I would expect it might hold some hints about how to handle that well. But law is just guidelines, and the rationality really derives from a human in the loop pulling the strings, judge or jurry. It&#8217;s not a system itself really so much as an extension and recording of the will of the judges to keep them from having to repeat themselves. So I keep coming back to the non-human systems to try to find isolated systems that heal well. Insect behavior is one of the classic examples, ants and bees.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[George Bush Jr More Evil Than Cthulhu]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/04/21/george-bush-jr-more-evil-than-cthulhu/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-21T06:04:39-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/04/21/george-bush-jr-more-evil-than-cthulhu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wow, folks really hate this <a href="http://lesserevil.ning.com/detail.php?DetailID=425486">George Bush Jr.</a> guy. You would think he roamed around in the streets killing puppies and kicking children or something. I check out the stats for <a href="http://browse.ning.com/any/miker/any/any">all my Ning apps</a> on a daily basis. Cause I&#8217;m vain, no sense in trying to justify it with anything else. And <a href="http://lesserevil.ning.com">LesserEvil</a> had a bunch of hits from Google image searches, searches for Georgie there. So I pull up his detail page and what do I see? &#8220;Cthulhu is less evil than George Bush Jr. 100% of the time.&#8221; Wow, that&#8217;s pretty evil. Or maybe it&#8217;s just interesting commentary on the mindset of folks in the &#8220;online and searching for random stuff cause I have that kind of time on my hands&#8221; segment of the population.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Jerry Taylor]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/04/03/more-jerry-taylor/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-03T01:51:06-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/04/03/more-jerry-taylor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some <a href="http://www.tuttletimes.com/siteSearch/apstorysection/local_story_088201244.html">additional info about the politician who incorrectly threatened CentOS with FBI action</a>. Gotta love this:</p>

<blockquote><p>“This is just a bunch of freaks out there that don’t have anything better to do,” he said. “When I came in to work Monday morning, I had about 500 e-mails, plus anonymous phone calls from all the geeks out there. [CentOS is] a free operating system that this guy gives away, which tells you how much time he’s got on his hands.”</p></blockquote>

<p>Nice, very nice. Unfortunately we can&#8217;t all resort to threats and scare tactics to get our work done for us. Or can we&#8230;.?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[High Availability NFS]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/04/03/high-availability-nfs/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-03T01:38:10-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/04/03/high-availability-nfs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve tried out the <a href="http://www.howtoforge.com/high_availability_nfs_drbd_heartbeat">high availability NFS solution detailed here</a> and run into a few issues. It does provide a great way to get a higher degree of availability for one of the most problematic bits of infrastructure, so I don&#8217;t mean to crap on the idea as a whole. But here are two issues to make sure you either check out or understand before you deploy something like this:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>We saw write throughput cut in half when DRBD was up and running. If you&#8217;ve got plenty of capacity and can segment as you grow you might be more concerned with the availability than the throughput. And it&#8217;s certainly possible that we could have performed some tuning to get DRBD to perform better. I&#8217;m just saying perform some benchmarks beforehand and afterward to make sure you&#8217;re not impacting the system too negatively without knowing it.</p></li>
<li><p>This is a block level replication technique, so there&#8217;s no guarantee that a filesystem level error that causes corruption isn&#8217;t just replicated over to the failover box as it happens. True, it&#8217;s much more common that the failure mode be bad blocks at the hardware level than an error at the OS level&#8230;. but once again this is block level replication. A bad block on the master side that goes undetected for even a single read/write cycle will have that incorrect information replicated to the slave. As far as I know (and I admit I haven&#8217;t researched this in a while) there isn&#8217;t a Linux filesystem that does end to end checksumming to prevent this kind of issue.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Just two things to keep in mind. There&#8217;s some great info in that article in general, like moving the NFS runtime files out to the replicated block device and how to configure heartbeat.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
