<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Entrepreneur | Miker]]></title>
  <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/categories/entrepreneur/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rowehl.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-29T07:13:02-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://rowehl.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mike Rowehl]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rebooting an Engineering Organization]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2013/05/25/rebooting-an-engineering-organization/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-25T00:06:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2013/05/25/rebooting-an-engineering-organization</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When Metaresolver got purchased by Millennial Media I figured I would have
some bits of strategic input around how to approach the evolving mobile media
models, and then I would help hack through some of the prototypes and early
systems in those new lines of business. That version was interesting cause of
the market position that Millennial has, and because it's been a really long
time since I've worked with a group larger than 10 people. But I had assumed
that the challenging part was going to be keeping myself from getting
overly bored by the rate of progress so I could hang out long enough to
make a difference.</p>

<p>And then when our deal actually formally closed the founding CTO from
Millennial left at the same time. In the wake of
that the decision was made: it was time for a major restructuring on the
technology side of Millennial. The company has a tremendous market position,
but we've been having trouble capitalizing on it. We needed to start
updating the way Millennial practices engineering so that it could keep at
the front of a rapidly evolving market. Suddenly being bored wasn't on my
list of concerns any more.</p>

<p>The part of the reboot that I've been most actively involved in is down in the
technical details of revamping how engineers get their daily work done. There
are some really simple parts that everyone has already been talking about
forever, and just needed some focused attention. Not everything is running
through a continuous integration process, and lots of it doesn't have
automated testing it can be run through. The organization as a whole has
fallen so far into the antipatterns of manual QA and the
<a href="http://www.rendell.org/pebble/software/2010/02/09/1265756844985.html">high ceremony release vehicle</a>
that there's a ton of resistance around fixing the deployment process. But
fortunately it's 2013 now, even in Baltimore. So hopefully it's just a matter
of time before everyone understands the value of getting working code up into
production quickly, and that there are better ways to make sure we enforce the
"working code" bit than throwing bodies and forms at the issue.</p>

<p>The overall goal is to get us to something that looks much more like a
continuous delivery process. There are some patterns that are just so second
nature to me and everyone I've worked with over the last few years that I
frequently forget they're not universal yet. Everything I've worked on over
the last few years has evolved in relatively the same direction: deployments
are single script (or single git push) affairs, the scripts write some
info into a shared channel so that people know what went out, the operational
monitors are visible to everyone and well defined, and rolling back if those
monitors go sideways is always part of the plan. It's awesome.</p>

<p>So when I ask someone about deployment tools and they start to describe
something that has a cabal of approvers meeting to bless things and change
notification forms I can only stand there stunned. Well, first I throw up in
my mouth a little bit, and then I stand there stunned.</p>

<p>Guess this is what I get for leaving Silicon Valley without proper backup.
It's a backwards and fucked up place out here my friends, and I can't
say I recommend it at all. But I've started to pull together the
necessary backup and my plan is to fix at least a small part of it before
my next startup. You're welcome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I Suck at Angel Investing, and My Plan]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2013/03/09/why-i-suck-at-angel-investing/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-09T21:23:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2013/03/09/why-i-suck-at-angel-investing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've done a bunch of angel investing over the last few years. And I've decided
I'm no good at it. The market, so far, seems to agree with me. Most of the
investments I've done are nowhere, frequently not even making it to launch.
That's okay actually, not a big deal.</p>

<p>What the realization has forced me to do is cycle back on why I was angel
investing in the first place. I really wanted to do it so that I could help
friends realize their dreams. There are tons of people I've worked with over
the years who have fantastic skills and often correspondingly focused vision.
That sounded like a great investment thesis to me, folks who I've worked with
directly.
And I figured that giving them
some money to help out when they were starting on a new effort would be a great
way to share in the adventure.</p>

<p>However, there's a bunch of stuff I missed the first time around:</p>

<ul>
<li>I'm bad at filtering ideas. I think everything is a good idea. That seems to
just be a bias of exuberance and having been an operator myself for the last
20 years. I project how I would attack the problems, and assume if it's
something I can execute on certainly other people can. In retrospect that was
dumb, and I should have realized this one in advance.</li>
<li>I thought I would be able to directly help out. I've been building businesses
and technology for 20 years, I normally have a lot to contribute. However,
once I'm an investor teams tend not to come back to me for help.
I think cause most of them only want to come back with good news, they're
kinda embarrassed to come back to an investor for help. That's just dumb on
their part. I use my investors for help all the time, and they're always
supportive, encouraging, and effective. Trying to run success theatre is dumb.</li>
<li>Venture funded businesses, and the current crop of startups in particular,
are really focused on short term financial gain. There's not really much
"realizing dreams". Unless your dream is to flip a company to Google. So it's
ended up being kinda boring. If it was even in there to begin with, vision
frequently takes a back seat. And the companies just randomly pivot over and
over, flailing around trying to find instant product market fit and 10x
compounding daily growth cause they think it's rational to expect that. Of
course they never do.</li>
<li>At the levels I've been investing (normally very small stuff like $10k to
$25k, the occasional $50k) it just doesn't shift the needle. Coupled with
folks not coming back for help: I'm not getting any leverage out of the
investment and the teams aren't getting any leverage out of the money.</li>
</ul>


<p>So, of course, the real next question should be how do I fix it? I could just
give up on trying to make awesome things happen. But that's not really my style.
I've also been tempted to dust off lots of stuff I learned from Churn Labs and
try to run a similar effort, with significant tweaks this time around. That
whole line of thinking is worth a post of its own actually.</p>

<p>Recently I had to do some legal work that required me to actually go through
and enumerate all my assets in one place. So the shares I have in companies
that I've invested in ended up side by side with the list of companies I have
shares from cause I'm advising them. And the difference was shocking. The folks
I spend a bit of time with every month, they're rocking it. That says to me
there might be something to me being able to directly help out. Now correlation
is not causation, I'm fully aware. So it might just be that the folks who
aren't asking me for money are predisposed to a working style that increases the
chance of success, and it really doesn't have anything to do with me at all. But
right now it's a working hypothesis at least, and I'm willing to test it.</p>

<p>There are actually a bunch of different methodologies I've been thinking about
to put that test into play. But then my current company got bought (which, by
the way, I'm using as an additional point in support of my hypothesis :-P), and
for once I'm finally enthusiastic about working with the new team for a good
chunk of time. So that severely cuts down on the plans I can realistically put
into action over the next few years.</p>

<p>That means if I want to keep involved it really needs to be as investor, but I
needed to figure out how to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Work on things that are going to change the world in a positive way, and that
me and the team will be proud of.</li>
<li>Make sure there's a way to keep myself directly involved, so I can figure out
if I actually make a difference at all. I need to figure out a nice
scientific approach to determine this still.</li>
<li>Provide real leverage to the teams.</li>
</ul>


<p>There are tons of incubators and accelerators out there now, and I didn't want
to be just another "me too" in a sea of mediocrity. Fortunately they tend to
really focus on different businesses than I would like to go after, so I'm
thinking I can do something that isn't duplicative. There are tons and tons of
little companies spun up to try to exploit tiny gaps in existing markets, and
relatively few looking to open up new areas. In other words there aren't too
many <a href="http://www.spacex.com/">SpaceX</a> style projects out there. And I would
like there to be.</p>

<p>My plan is to start filtering the projects I work
with using a completely different set of criteria going forward, to take a much
more active and direct role in the projects, and to start investing in the
$250k to $500k range instead. I've got one of these starting to come together
now, and a few other discussions with folks about the overall model. I think
the right model for myself is actually to keep this to one project at a time,
just to keep myself and the team focused. So I'm probably going to also start
being a lot more low volume than I have been in the past.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
