<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Dweeb | Miker]]></title>
  <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/categories/dweeb/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rowehl.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-14T18:40:45-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://rowehl.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mike Rowehl]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HOPE Six Audio Online]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/08/25/hope-six-audio-online/"/>
    <updated>2006-08-25T02:57:27-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/08/25/hope-six-audio-online</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The full <a href="http://www.hopenumbersix.net/speakers.html">set of audio from the HOPE six conference</a> is online now. The conf happened just before DEFCON and I hear it has some fantastic stuff that didn't show up in Vegas. Download and share!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Picture of the Enzo Driver]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/02/23/picture-of-the-enzo-driver/"/>
    <updated>2006-02-23T05:33:26-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/02/23/picture-of-the-enzo-driver</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Most of you have probably heard about <a href="http://www.edmunds.com/insideline/do/News/articleId=109393">the Enzo Ferrari crash yesterday</a>. Sad sad thing to see such a beautiful car destroyed. If you're feeling like gawking you can check out the <a href="http://www.jalopnik.com/cars/news/more-on-the-enzo-incident-on-pch-with-photos-156121.php">pictures of the crash site here</a>. Fortunately I can also bring you exclusive coverage, one of my friends down in the area snapped a pic of the real Enzo driver as he escaped into the woods:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.skepsis.nl/bigfoot.jpg" alt="Dietrich" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[100 Cups of Coffee]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/01/05/100-cups-of-coffee/"/>
    <updated>2006-01-05T03:38:23-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2006/01/05/100-cups-of-coffee</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started using <a href="http://www.43things.com">43Things</a> finally, and one of my goals is to <a href="http://www.43things.com/things/view/301170">drink 100 cups of coffee</a>. This is in homage to <a href="http://www.gotfuturama.com/Information/Capsules/4ACV16/">the Futurama episode where Fry drinks 100 cups of coffee</a> and reaches some kind of enlightenment. Sure, it's a cartoon and all, but it still looked like fun. And I think it's important to have goals, no matter how inane they might be. Most people say something like "you know it is possible to overdose on caffeine?" or "that would probably kill you". Generally discouraging remarks. But thanks to Wikipedia I think I might be looking at a plausible goal. Check out the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caffeine">caffeine entry</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LD50">LD</a>50 of caffeine is estimated between 13 and 19 grams for oral administration for an average adult. The LD50 of caffeine is dependent on weight and individual sensitivity and estimated to be about 150 to 200 mg per kg of body mass, roughly 140 to 180 cups of coffee for an average adult taken within a limited timeframe that is dependent on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Half-life#Half-life_in_chemistry">half-life</a>. The half-life, or time it takes for the amount of caffeine in the blood to decrease by 50%, ranges from 3.5 to 10 hours. In adults the half-life is generally around 5 hours. However, contraceptive pills increase this to around 12 hours, and, for women over 3 months pregnant, it varies from 10 to 18 hours. In infants and young children, the half-life may be longer than in adults. With common coffee and a very rare half-life of 100 hours, it would require 3 cups of coffee every hour for 100 hours just to reach LD50.</p></blockquote>

<p>3 cups of coffee every hour for 100 hours, see that? And my goal is just 2 cups of coffee for 48 hours. That should be well below the lethal dosage. I just got a large capacity coffee maker for home, I'm thinking this would be a great way to test it out. 2006 has been a great year so far and we're not even a week in. How much would it rock to knock down a long standing goal before the end of January? A lot, that's how much.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lesser Evil]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2005/10/26/lesser-evil/"/>
    <updated>2005-10-26T10:21:51-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2005/10/26/lesser-evil</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the things I hear pretty often is "sometimes you just have to go with the lesser evil". Now, granted, I probably tend to get myself into situations that would spark that remark more often than is normal. But I'm sure most of you have heard it somewhere along the line. It's not like that really solves anything though. Evil is supposed to be all trixie and insidious. Make you think you're doing good when you're really doing evil. The ol' bait and switch. If I knew which was the lesser evil I wouldn't be pondering in the first place. So instead of pondering I just built an app to help: <a href="http://lesserevil.ning.com">Lesser Evil</a>. So that I can find out what everyone else's take on Lesser Evil is. Should help right around election time. And I threw Cthulhu and Evil Lincoln in there as controls, cause everyone knows nothings really more evil than Evil Lincoln except Cthulhu. So if they end getting voted the lesser evil I know all you people are lying.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coroutines (Navel Gazing Warning)]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2005/10/07/coroutines-navel-gazing-warning/"/>
    <updated>2005-10-07T20:42:18-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2005/10/07/coroutines-navel-gazing-warning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://it.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=05/10/06/2223232&amp;from=rss">This mention of lightweight cooperative multithreading and coroutines</a> caught my eye for some reason. Maybe cause it's been a while since I wrote anything in C and I got a patch this morning for one of my open source palm programs. Which of course got me thinking about programs that write programs, a concept which gets discovered and rediscovered often enough that I think I've seen it about a half dozen times in my relatively short career. Given <a href="http://www.ning.com">the new gig</a> I've been thinking a lot about domain specific languages, abstraction, and metaprogramming. In particular I've been thinking about the tradeoffs between mature systems that exhibit good abstraction and the cut-and-paste reuse that most people instinctively sneer at. Programming in C actually tends to mix the two styles quite a bit. C code tends to be maleable because of the tools available to shape it, the (often abused) macro facility, and the ability to do just about anything you want with your types if you use pointers. Watching something like the Linux kernel evolve through sets of patches makes you realize that there is a metalanguage in the deltas. Over time interface points in the code shift and join, moving from interfaces used in change sets to interfaces instantiated in the model of the program itself.</p>

<p>So how do you encourage the same maleable programming when you have a bunch of independent programs? Can the same cut-and-paste evolution style that helped grow the web take hold in application code? The coroutines implemented in a bunch of tricky C code are relatively easily represented <a href="http://gd.tuwien.ac.at/languages/scheme/tutorial-dsitaram/t-y-scheme-Z-H-14.html">in scheme using continuation passing style</a>. When do you implement using C and when do you push the function down into the language itself? I'm just wondering in writing at this point, I don't have any answers to this one.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
