<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Silicon Valley | Miker]]></title>
  <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/categories/silicon-valley/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rowehl.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-25T01:15:11-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://rowehl.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mike Rowehl]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tagcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2005/10/31/tagcamp/"/>
    <updated>2005-10-31T19:36:34-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2005/10/31/tagcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I went to <a href="http://www.tagcamp.org/">Tagcamp</a> this past weekend, fantastic event. I met a ton of new people, which is always fun. A lot of great information and new projects. Although I missed her presentation, I found out about Rashmi's <a href="http://www.rashmisinha.com/archives/05_09/tagging-cognitive.html">cognitive analysis of tagging</a> while I was there. I think the two images there explain why tagging is different than categorization better than anything else I've seen before. The session that <a href="http://marshallk.com/">Marshall Kirkpatrick</a> was very lively. The conversation focused on making tagging more accessible to users. If tagging really is a different model for organizing information how can we provide that in a way that doesn't include a large cliff to adoption? Some of the folks proposed getting together sets of user stories as a start to finding the common bits and root drivers for successful adoption. Unfortunately I can't find where anyone has written down that tag, the notes from the session seem to have gotten rightly fucked. Anyone have another copy of the notes floating around on a hard drive?</p>

<p>Mike Prince from <a href="http://www.mobido.com">Mobido</a> spoke some about the tag system they have for creating group conversations, and at the end of his conversation we branched out some and spoke in general about tagging systems and mobility. I'm always interested in what I call "closing the feedback loop". Systems and techniques that make it possible to both publish and consume from a mobile device. Tagging systems, and the associated models that go along with them, seem like they would be well suited to supporting a fully mobile system. The demo from <a href="http://www.photo-router.com/">PhotoRouter</a> later on in the day provided an example of one form that could take. Users sending photos can tag those images with whatever they want, no setting of categories in advance necessary. Receivers can opt into receiving photos with a given tag when they receive something they like. Now if they start sending photos to the group with a tag influenced by what they've gotten recently that's the kind of direct in-the-field interaction I think we're going to keep seeing more and more of.  There's a swarming kind of behavior that takes place with tagging, and being able to see other peoples tags as you tag yourself is a big part of that. I think it's the reason that tag/heat maps get so much attention, cause they provide the information about hotspots at a glance and help drive the convergence that turns tagging from noise into collaborative filtering.</p>

<p>There was a bunch of interest in making tagging more generic. Tagging tends to be something that you do with the major content of a system. <a href="http://del.icio.us">del.icio.us</a> lets you add tags to bookmarks, <a href="http://www.flickr.com">Flickr</a> allows tags for photos. But should you be able to tag users? Tag collections? Tag any object? Tag other tags? General consensus seemed to be yes, you should be able to. <a href="http://toetag.sourceforge.net/">Toetag</a> is a project setup to attempt to create a generic system for providing such a system as a standard component. There were some others working on somewhat similar systems, but I only caught the Toetag presentation unfortunately. We've had that conversation at Ning a few times, and it's one of the reasons that tags are a fundamental function of the system. I was happy to hear that we weren't off in the weeds conceptually, and that if anything we should be making that functionality more generic.</p>

<p>Thanks to everyone involved in getting Tagcamp together! It was a great event, and I think most people got a lot of great information out of it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tag Tuesday Tomorrow]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2005/09/26/tag-tuesday-tomorrow/"/>
    <updated>2005-09-26T10:27:03-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2005/09/26/tag-tuesday-tomorrow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm planning to head up to the city tomorrow to meet up with some folks in town for <a href="http://www.wirelessit.com/">CTIA San Francisco</a>, and Niall pointed out that <a href="http://www.tagtuesday.com/index.php/2005/09/23/tag-tuesday-september-meeting/">Tag Tuesday</a> is tomorrow too.  I haven't been out and about all that much lately, so I'm hoping to catch up with a whole bunch of people. If you're gonna be somewhere around Soma tomorrow in the evening give me a ring or send me a message.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oral History of Silicon Valley]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2005/09/19/oral-history-or-silicon-valley/"/>
    <updated>2005-09-19T22:14:59-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2005/09/19/oral-history-or-silicon-valley</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I listened to <a href="http://www.itconversations.com/shows/detail595.html">John Markoff's talk from the SDForum</a> while I was wandering around, and decided that it was too good of a collection of references about Silicon Valley not to have my own pointers online. I'll have to pick up the book also, sounds like it'll be great. Meantime, here's a set of pointers to stuff (people, places, things) that's at least refferenced in the audio:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ted_Nelson">Ted Nelson</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Douglas_Englebart">Douglas Englebart</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.bootstrap.org/augdocs/friedewald030402/augmentinghumanintellect/ahi62index.html">Augmenting Human Intellect: A Conceptual Framework</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Augmentation_Research_Center">Augmentation Research Center</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www-formal.stanford.edu/jmc/">John McCarthy</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://ai.stanford.edu/people.html">Stanford Artificial Intelligence Labratory</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.accessexcellence.org/RC/AB/BC/Kary_B_Mullis.html">Kary Mullis</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phil_Lesh">Phil Lesh</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whole_earth_catalog">Whole Earth Catalog</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.digibarn.com/collections/newsletters/peoples-computer/">People's Computer Company</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homebrew_Computer_Club">Homebrew Computer Club</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Larry_Tesler">Larry Tesler</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://sloan.stanford.edu/mousesite/EngelbartPapers/B10_F39_MicroSimili.html">Microelectronics, and the Art of Similitude</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NLS_%28computer_system%29">NLS</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.edge.org/3rd_culture/bios/brand.html">Stewart Brand</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://research.sun.com/people/diffie/">Whitfield Diffie</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spacewar">Spacewar</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.wheels.org/spacewar/stone/rolling_stone.html">Fanatic Life and Symbolic Death Among the Computer Bums</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.cognitiveliberty.org/pressroom/myron_stolaroff.htm">Myron Stolaroff</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alfred_Matthew_Hubbard">Captain Al Hubbard</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Kay">Alan Kay</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://opencollector.org/history/homebrew/Chapter9.html">Fred Moore</a></p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search SIG]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2005/09/15/search-sig/"/>
    <updated>2005-09-15T11:04:48-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2005/09/15/search-sig</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.sdforum.org/SDForum/Templates/CalendarEvent.aspx?CID=1754&amp;mo=9&amp;yr=2005">first meeting of the Search SIG from SDForum</a> was last night. The new forum is run by <a href="http://www.500hats.com/sys-tmpl/door/">Dave McClure</a> and <a href="http://blog.softtechvc.com/">Jeff Clavier</a>. They did a great job on this first event, and I'm really looking forward to our combined Search SIG and Mobile Monday event happening next month. I only seen <a href="http://www.horsepigcow.com/2005/09/search-sig-yahoo.html">one posting so far</a>. After <a href="http://www.niallkennedy.com/blog/">Niall</a> and <a href="http://feedblog.org/">Kevin</a> vying for attention during the announcements, I figured they would represent with a summary or something.  Here's mine.</p>

<p>The main section of the presentation was a panel lead by Doug Kaye from <a href="http://www.itconversations.com/index.html">IT Conversations</a>. Doug started out pretty early drawing a distinction between different kinds of audio search, with the main distinction being between directories of audio and search services that actually look at the audio and try to index it. <a href="http://www.podscope.com/">Podscope</a> and <a href="http://www.blinkx.com/overview.php">Blinkx</a> were mentioned in particular. Podscope is used frequently by companies looking for mentions of their name or products. There was one other mentioned, but I must have gotten the name wrong. If someone knows it please leave me a comment, I'll update the post. Jeff from Yahoo drew a distinction between phonetic search and text recovery search. Making a transcript from audio gives you text that you can search, but frequently gives garbage back if the audio quality is poor or there's a lot of noise. Phonetic search tends to give better results, but doesn't give you text to work with. He also pointed out that closed captioning is another fantastic source of info if you're dealing with media where that's available. Someone joked that closed captioning tends to be highly innacurate, but apparently there's a mandate (FCC?) that requires some minimal degree of accuracy (97%?) for closed captioning on TV broadcasts.</p>

<p>Eric Rice from <a href="http://www.audioblog.com">Audioblog.com</a> (recently funded) made that point that most podcasts appear with some kind of text, and getting that text indexed is the key to getting your content found. He said he personally hasn't had trouble getting his content found. He likes tagging, even though it has a way to go to be a mature technique. In his opinion extracting text from audio isn't a great technique, you lose lots of nuance like sarcasm. When asked about directories he said that as a publisher he doesn't like that there are so many directories to deal with. ITunes is really the big kid on the block when you think about directories. The inclusion of podcasts in the ITunes setup doubled traffic for lots of folks. Eric also gets people coming into his site from searches that hit his show notes. He also tends to tag his own stuff on <a href="http://del.icio.us">del.icio.us</a> to bootstrap it.</p>

<p>David Marks from <a href="http://www.loomia.com/">Loomia</a> spoke about the different kinds of things that are searched for. Enterprises search for mentions of their name, but people tend to search for things like music. Conversion to text just isn't going to help at all when it comes to something like finding music. Loomia attempts to do that through recommendation and collaborative filtering. It helps you to find the things you didn't know to search for. Timeliness is very important with blogs, but it hasn't hit yet with audio. It will hit with audio, and that should be very interesting. Audio search is very much unlike traditional search because the cost of scanning results is much higher. It's not like a page you can scan with excerpts randomly clicking through to see which is the right one. Starting up an audio stream and checking to see if it fits your needs is a much more cumbersome activity.</p>

<p>There was some talk about <a href="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss">Media RSS</a>, extensions to RSS spearheaded by Yahoo. Media RSS aims to provide additional information about rich media to be transported along with RSS feeds. It's meant to help democratize the creation of rich media, but currently people have to be pretty techy to use it. Eric said there was really a need for vendors to create tools that emit this kind of extra information with a single click of a button or toggle of a checkbox. It's what they did with Audioblog for the ITunes extensions. There's a very simple checkbox that allows people to include the extended attributes in the information that Audioblog emits for them. Normal people can't and don't want to edit RSS. Dave from Loomia said that as an aggregator you really have to eat garbage and poo gold. You have to take in all kinds of errors that the user makes in putting up their info, and provide perfectly correct information to your consumers. It would be great if people validated their feeds, but they don't. And it would be dumb to expect them to. It would be great though. Character set problems are very common. Doug said he's run into a lot of character set issues as well.</p>

<p>There was some discussion about the ITunes release that doubled traffic. It happened right around the beginning of July. Apple didn't tell anyone what was going on though. They sucked in the wrong feeds, and none of the podcasters knew about the ITunes extensions cause they weren't public at that point. As a result the podcast info in the ITunes directory looked like crap. But most people forgave it cause it doubled their traffic.</p>

<p>Ev (from <a href="http://www.odeo.com/">Odeo</a>) made a point about the key to getting found having nothing to do with technology, it's all about being unique and having interesting things to say. If you do that people will find their way to what you post. He also said that Odeo isn't really looking at the creation of text to go along with the audio they do. Most current podcasters think of their website/blog as the home of their audio, but Odeo really wants to go after the very non-technical users who don't have a site to associate with. They just want audio.</p>

<p>Eric mentioned that mobile devices also don't really encourage the use of text. Blogging behavior really doesn't apply when most of the consumption of the audio is being done on iPods and other audio players. People aren't going to link or trackback from their iPod. Eric said that everything that Audioblog does for audio, they do for video as well. He's a big believer in video. Ev said that he wasn't as enthusiastic about it however, cause the consumption devices aren't as widespread. There are portable audio players all over the place, but no so for video. Doug also made the point that audio already dominates drive time and exercise time, there's an existing consumption model for audio.</p>

<p>Then there was a quick break and there were demos from Loomia, Odeo, and Audioblog. Great demos actually, I really liked this part of the session. I liked the part about the consumption model for audio vs. video. What podcasting allows people to do is pour more interesting content into the time when they're driving or exercising. Definitely makes a lot of sense. But the same thing is true for video. There is a built in consumption model there. Lots of people sit around in the evening and channel or tivo surf for an hour or two after dinner or before bed. Would the same thing apply if we were able to pour content from online into that space. Of course, it would have to come in to something that would allow it to be displayed in the same way, it would have to appear on your television and not your computer screen. That might not be true in Asia however, where usage of mobile devices is already pretty well positioned for something like video delivery. There has been some effort already to provide this kind of service, I think specificly about both <a href="http://www.akimbo.com/">Akimbo</a> and <a href="http://www.pvrblog.com/pvr/2004/09/newsweek_netfli.html">some efforts by Tivo</a> when I say this, but I don't think anyone has really crossed the line into videocasting like this. Can I subscribe to a Media RSS feed if I get an Akimbo box?</p>

<p>I think someone like <a href="http://www.mobitv.com/">MobiTV</a> would be pretty well served by thinking about stuff like this. Mobile video makes sense, but only if there are clips and snippets of the right size worth watching. Clips and snippets of the right size are generally just about movie trailer or commercial length (I know some folks really think the ideal video length for mobile consumption is 4 to 5 minutes, but I disagree). People generally aren't going to pay for those little videos however. Do I want to pay $3 to $10 to watch a few minutes of video on my phone? Hell no. So you need a different way to make money off that content. How about putting commercials in? No, when the slices of time you have to fill are short already no one wants to wait for commercials to go along with their content. So how about making the whole video clip a commercial? "What the hell are you talking about?" you might say. How about if the video clips that MobiTV carried were basically just coming attractions and short versions of longer content?  If I download a clip via MobiTV, for free, and I like what I just saw I can opt to use my IP DRV at home to download the main content (a new movie, a television show, whatever). Television already runs cross promotion on television in order to get folks to change the channel to whatever it is they're pimping. How about paying to pimp it on mobiles as well. If the content were done right I think people might actually enjoy the bits they get on their mobile, and because they get it for free they'll be a lot happier with what they do get. It would basicly be using your mobile as a video remote control for your DVR at home. You can whip it out when you have a few minutes free and check out recomendations and new additions instead of doing that part with the remote control while sitting on the couch. When you select stuff you want it activates the box at home that starts downloading. And by the time you park your ass in front of the tube you have a hot steaming dose of fresh video cache to stimulate and amuse and rock you to sleep. Sounds like a good idea to me at least.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href="http://www.bitsplitter.net/tag.php/searchsig">searchsig</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Innovation Disconnect]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2005/09/07/innovation-disconnect/"/>
    <updated>2005-09-07T05:26:10-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2005/09/07/innovation-disconnect</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I see stories like <a href="http://hardware.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=05/09/03/2011200&amp;from=rss">this one about 4G cell phone services being worked on with gigabit data rates</a> and <a href="http://slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=05/09/04/1410253&amp;from=rss">this one with doubts about consumers really wanting digital homes</a> and overall I'm left wondering about the ability of the market to deliver innovation. Would I like gigabit data rates to my phone? Of course, why not? Would I be willing to pay the equivalently scaled up cost of $200K per month in order to do so ($20 per month for 100Kbps being vaguely equivalent to $200,000 per month for 1,000,000Kbps or 1Gbps)? No, of course I wouldn't. In many ways the technical achievement in these fields has outstripped the ability of markets and products to deliver them to end users. Innovation is good, seemingly unrelated discoveries sometimes lead to fantastic breakthroughs, and the only way to get that to happen is to let the passionate people keep hacking away on the things they love. But there's also a very real sense of doubt when I hear about this stuff. I was supposed to have gigabit wired connections available at home. It was supposed to give me instant access to all the world media at the click of a button. I think it would be fair to say that vision was unrealistic. So when I hear that I could get gigabit to my handset soon I can't help but think "Wow, I would like to just consistently get my 100Kbps all the way from Palo Alto to San Francisco on the train without constant service drops." And think sarcasticly that the real driver for the enhanced data rate is that telcos think their profits will scale with the data rate because now people can download more ringtones. When in reality if they want to sell more ringtones the limiting factor has nothing to do with bandwidth. It has to do with user interface and cost and customer awareness and compelling product. I would guess that bandwidth is somewhere down around 20th in terms of contributing factors.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
