<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Startup | Miker]]></title>
  <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/categories/startup/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rowehl.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-24T19:23:25-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://rowehl.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mike Rowehl]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I Suck at Angel Investing, and My Plan]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2013/03/09/why-i-suck-at-angel-investing/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-09T21:23:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2013/03/09/why-i-suck-at-angel-investing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've done a bunch of angel investing over the last few years. And I've decided
I'm no good at it. The market, so far, seems to agree with me. Most of the
investments I've done are nowhere, frequently not even making it to launch.
That's okay actually, not a big deal.</p>

<p>What the realization has forced me to do is cycle back on why I was angel
investing in the first place. I really wanted to do it so that I could help
friends realize their dreams. There are tons of people I've worked with over
the years who have fantastic skills and often correspondingly focused vision.
That sounded like a great investment thesis to me, folks who I've worked with
directly.
And I figured that giving them
some money to help out when they were starting on a new effort would be a great
way to share in the adventure.</p>

<p>However, there's a bunch of stuff I missed the first time around:</p>

<ul>
<li>I'm bad at filtering ideas. I think everything is a good idea. That seems to
just be a bias of exuberance and having been an operator myself for the last
20 years. I project how I would attack the problems, and assume if it's
something I can execute on certainly other people can. In retrospect that was
dumb, and I should have realized this one in advance.</li>
<li>I thought I would be able to directly help out. I've been building businesses
and technology for 20 years, I normally have a lot to contribute. However,
once I'm an investor teams tend not to come back to me for help.
I think cause most of them only want to come back with good news, they're
kinda embarrassed to come back to an investor for help. That's just dumb on
their part. I use my investors for help all the time, and they're always
supportive, encouraging, and effective. Trying to run success theatre is dumb.</li>
<li>Venture funded businesses, and the current crop of startups in particular,
are really focused on short term financial gain. There's not really much
"realizing dreams". Unless your dream is to flip a company to Google. So it's
ended up being kinda boring. If it was even in there to begin with, vision
frequently takes a back seat. And the companies just randomly pivot over and
over, flailing around trying to find instant product market fit and 10x
compounding daily growth cause they think it's rational to expect that. Of
course they never do.</li>
<li>At the levels I've been investing (normally very small stuff like $10k to
$25k, the occasional $50k) it just doesn't shift the needle. Coupled with
folks not coming back for help: I'm not getting any leverage out of the
investment and the teams aren't getting any leverage out of the money.</li>
</ul>


<p>So, of course, the real next question should be how do I fix it? I could just
give up on trying to make awesome things happen. But that's not really my style.
I've also been tempted to dust off lots of stuff I learned from Churn Labs and
try to run a similar effort, with significant tweaks this time around. That
whole line of thinking is worth a post of its own actually.</p>

<p>Recently I had to do some legal work that required me to actually go through
and enumerate all my assets in one place. So the shares I have in companies
that I've invested in ended up side by side with the list of companies I have
shares from cause I'm advising them. And the difference was shocking. The folks
I spend a bit of time with every month, they're rocking it. That says to me
there might be something to me being able to directly help out. Now correlation
is not causation, I'm fully aware. So it might just be that the folks who
aren't asking me for money are predisposed to a working style that increases the
chance of success, and it really doesn't have anything to do with me at all. But
right now it's a working hypothesis at least, and I'm willing to test it.</p>

<p>There are actually a bunch of different methodologies I've been thinking about
to put that test into play. But then my current company got bought (which, by
the way, I'm using as an additional point in support of my hypothesis :-P), and
for once I'm finally enthusiastic about working with the new team for a good
chunk of time. So that severely cuts down on the plans I can realistically put
into action over the next few years.</p>

<p>That means if I want to keep involved it really needs to be as investor, but I
needed to figure out how to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Work on things that are going to change the world in a positive way, and that
me and the team will be proud of.</li>
<li>Make sure there's a way to keep myself directly involved, so I can figure out
if I actually make a difference at all. I need to figure out a nice
scientific approach to determine this still.</li>
<li>Provide real leverage to the teams.</li>
</ul>


<p>There are tons of incubators and accelerators out there now, and I didn't want
to be just another "me too" in a sea of mediocrity. Fortunately they tend to
really focus on different businesses than I would like to go after, so I'm
thinking I can do something that isn't duplicative. There are tons and tons of
little companies spun up to try to exploit tiny gaps in existing markets, and
relatively few looking to open up new areas. In other words there aren't too
many <a href="http://www.spacex.com/">SpaceX</a> style projects out there. And I would
like there to be.</p>

<p>My plan is to start filtering the projects I work
with using a completely different set of criteria going forward, to take a much
more active and direct role in the projects, and to start investing in the
$250k to $500k range instead. I've got one of these starting to come together
now, and a few other discussions with folks about the overall model. I think
the right model for myself is actually to keep this to one project at a time,
just to keep myself and the team focused. So I'm probably going to also start
being a lot more low volume than I have been in the past.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use of Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2013/02/06/use-of-time/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-06T12:48:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2013/02/06/use-of-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love the idea behind social media services, helping to connect people and
strengthen relationships. However I don't think most are actually fulfilling
on that vision. Sure, you can stay connected with friends. But your goals and
the goals of the social service itself frequently aren't aligned. The desire
of social media services to drive the metrics they want based on your
connections to friends and family have resulted in systems that
prey on base urges. The result is systems that drive themselves off addiction
loops. In the end they're like overeating or
smoking, bad habits. And I assume most people will look to weed out those
behaviors in the interest of their overall health. That's my view at least, so
I took the plunge and deleted my Facebook account about a year ago.</p>

<p>At about the same time I decided to crank down a lot of my tech news
consumption, and filter down the folks I follow on Twitter to people who
regularly post things that are uniquely amusing or valuable. I had realized
what I was really trying to do was:</p>

<ul>
<li>make sure I had a good spread of new info coming in to keep generally informed</li>
<li>keep on top of what was going on in my industry</li>
</ul>


<p>So I focused on directly solving those problems instead of having
someone else try to correct for them by proxy. The first part was
kicking back up my long-form reading habit, I started downloading and
consuming lots of Kindle books. When we were working on Churn Labs I wanted to
learn more about places that created long periods with high levels of
innovation. In the info I was finding online I commonly came across the same
examples over and over. Places like Florence during the period of the Medici
family, or Apple, or Corning. But most of those posts online referenced
books for details. In following up the references and just trying to get some
details I picked up a few books and read them through.</p>

<p>At the time it had been a while since I sat down and read a book front to back
that wasn't either sci-fi or highly technical. I found that for the purposes
of "researching" something, trying to dig into a new topic and understanding
it well enough to be able to make a mental framework and form personal
opinions, I was getting a lot more out of just reading long-form writing.
When it comes to picking up a new subject most online resources don't do a
great job.
I think that's why there's so much attention right now
being thrown into "online learning." The Internet is a fantastic way to
keep up to date with a topic you already understand. But it's generally falling
flat when it comes to getting up to speed with something new. Fortunately for
me I pick things up relatively well in written form, and I'm pretty good at
filling in practical experience on my own. So when I hit something new,
sometimes I'll follow up the cursory Wikipedia overview with a book if the
topic seems interesting enough. It can get
to be an expensive habit, but I'm finding it to be well worth it.
Hopefully soon all these education startups will make free resources I can use
instead, but for now I'm sticking to the books.</p>

<p>Listening to podcasts has also helped a good deal with getting an overview.
A bunch of the topics I'm interesting in following at a high level. I don't
have the background to follow all the details of new info, but I like to at
least keep informed about major advances in science or engineering. Audio
format delivery seems to be great for that. Lots of the podcasters keep things
high level, I assume cause that's best suited to the medium. So
adding just a few shows like the Economist and Science Friday has made me feel
like I'm pretty well on top of all the stuff I really care about. And I just
use an app (Stitcher on Android for me) so I can listen to the shows while I
walk to/from the train station. Fills up time that wasn't really being well
utilized before.</p>

<p>Then I had to figure out how to keep up with the details of the industry
I'm working in. Or at least I thought I had to. Turns out that the generic
information sources plus directly operating in the industry was already
feeding me more than enough data. I lost a lot of noise by not following the
tech industry coverage. And I figured keeping on top of daily events was
necessary for conversations with other folks in the industry, otherwise you
seem ignorant when someone asks you about a hot topic.
But I found that with the noise gone I had stronger
opinions and better judgment anyway, and the discussions I had were actually
higher quality. Probably cause I had spent more time exploring and
validating my own viewpoint, so I had a lot more to contribute to
conversations.</p>

<p>Every now and again, there's something that's absolutely essential for me to
catch quickly. What I'm finding is that normally someone will forward it
to me. Usually to get my opinion on it.
And I find that cause I'm consuming things outside the channels most
folks pick through, I can serve that same role for others. Really, that's my
"social network" doing what I originally hoped it would do. Turns out the
social tools were standing in the way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
