<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Engineering | Miker]]></title>
  <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/categories/engineering/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rowehl.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-26T23:12:41-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://rowehl.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mike Rowehl]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rebooting an Engineering Organization]]></title>
    <link href="http://rowehl.com/blog/2013/05/25/rebooting-an-engineering-organization/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-25T00:06:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://rowehl.com/blog/2013/05/25/rebooting-an-engineering-organization</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When Metaresolver got purchased by Millennial Media I figured I would have
some bits of strategic input around how to approach the evolving mobile media
models, and then I would help hack through some of the prototypes and early
systems in those new lines of business. That version was interesting cause of
the market position that Millennial has, and because it's been a really long
time since I've worked with a group larger than 10 people. But I had assumed
that the challenging part was going to be keeping myself from getting
overly bored by the rate of progress so I could hang out long enough to
make a difference.</p>

<p>And then when our deal actually formally closed the founding CTO from
Millennial left at the same time. In the wake of
that the decision was made: it was time for a major restructuring on the
technology side of Millennial. The company has a tremendous market position,
but we've been having trouble capitalizing on it. We needed to start
updating the way Millennial practices engineering so that it could keep at
the front of a rapidly evolving market. Suddenly being bored wasn't on my
list of concerns any more.</p>

<p>The part of the reboot that I've been most actively involved in is down in the
technical details of revamping how engineers get their daily work done. There
are some really simple parts that everyone has already been talking about
forever, and just needed some focused attention. Not everything is running
through a continuous integration process, and lots of it doesn't have
automated testing it can be run through. The organization as a whole has
fallen so far into the antipatterns of manual QA and the
<a href="http://www.rendell.org/pebble/software/2010/02/09/1265756844985.html">high ceremony release vehicle</a>
that there's a ton of resistance around fixing the deployment process. But
fortunately it's 2013 now, even in Baltimore. So hopefully it's just a matter
of time before everyone understands the value of getting working code up into
production quickly, and that there are better ways to make sure we enforce the
"working code" bit than throwing bodies and forms at the issue.</p>

<p>The overall goal is to get us to something that looks much more like a
continuous delivery process. There are some patterns that are just so second
nature to me and everyone I've worked with over the last few years that I
frequently forget they're not universal yet. Everything I've worked on over
the last few years has evolved in relatively the same direction: deployments
are single script (or single git push) affairs, the scripts write some
info into a shared channel so that people know what went out, the operational
monitors are visible to everyone and well defined, and rolling back if those
monitors go sideways is always part of the plan. It's awesome.</p>

<p>So when I ask someone about deployment tools and they start to describe
something that has a cabal of approvers meeting to bless things and change
notification forms I can only stand there stunned. Well, first I throw up in
my mouth a little bit, and then I stand there stunned.</p>

<p>Guess this is what I get for leaving Silicon Valley without proper backup.
It's a backwards and fucked up place out here my friends, and I can't
say I recommend it at all. But I've started to pull together the
necessary backup and my plan is to fix at least a small part of it before
my next startup. You're welcome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
